다이간다는 방을 밝게 하고 적당히 떨어져서 봐!
Watch Daigunder in a bright room and keep some distance!
Смотри Дайгандера со включённым светом, сидя подальше от экрана!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
Дайгандер!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе,
마음의 눈을 열어라
Open your eyes of soul
Распахни шире око души
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
(Bakutou Sengen Daigunder)
Боевой претендент Дайгандер!
뜨거운 마음을 담아
With all your hot heart
Пусть меня охватит твой жар сердца,
오늘도 기적을 맹새해
I will make a miracle today too
Чтобы сотворить сумел я чудо
드래곤 소드 작렬이야
Dragon Sword bursts
Вспыхнет ярким светом Меч Дракона!
싸워야 할 라이벌은
The rival I have to fight against is
Побороть я должен свой упавший дух,
좌절하려는 내 자신
right here, dispirited myself
что пути к успеху преграждает мне,
어제보다도 진화해서
Evolve even more than yesterday
Вырасти сегодня больше, чем вчера
강해져라!
And become strong!
И сильнее стать!
다다다다 다 다 다 다다
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
Пушка Дракона!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе
에너지 전개로
Open up all your energy and
Дай энергии выход, сказав...
다다다다다다 다
Dadadadadada da
Дададададада-да!!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
쓰러트려라 타도해라
Defeat and knock down
Победи и врагов одолей
빛나는 강철의
Fighter of shining steel
Сталью сверкает тело твоё,
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
제 28 화
The 28th Episode
Эпизод 28
전직선언!
Job Change Declaration!
하루카는 일류 매니저!!
Haruka is a First Class Manager!!
(en: Maybe The Grass Ain't Greener)
아키라, 일어나! 아키라도 참!
Akira, wake up! Akira!
계속 자고 있지만 말고!
Don't keep sleeping like that!
좀만 더.
A little bit more...
일어나라니까!
Just wake up!
싫어!
No!
자! 둘 다 정신 차려!
Wake up, you two!
배고파!
I'm hungry!
지금 서봇이 만들고 있어.
Supbot is now preparing.
하루카, 어젯밤 부탁한 내 파트 말인데...
Haruka, about my part I asked you last night...
하루카, 왼팔이 찌리릿해모그!
Haruka, my left arm isn't feeling right-mogu!
괜찮을 거야. 곧 점검이야.
It'll be fine. It's your maintenance time soon anyway.
어디어디, 서봇 손이 비면 말해둘 테니까.
Let's see... I'll tell Supbot to check you out when he's free.
하루카, 어때, 오늘 나?
Haruka, how do I look today?
네, 네, 오늘도 멋져.
Yeah, yeah, you look good today too.
하루카, 내 배터리 수리는 어떻게 되고 있나?
Haruka, how is my battery repair going?
아, 렉스...
Oh, Rex...
잠깐만! 내가 먼저야!
Wait! I came first!
시끄러워! 보스의 배터리가 더 중요해!
Shut up! My boss' battery is more important!
-뭐야?!
-뭐야는 뭐야!
-What?!
-What is that what?!
너 태도가 거만하다모그!
You look impudent-mogu!
잠깐, 아침부터 싸우냐!
Stop it! You're beginning new day by fighting!
배고파!
I'm hungry!
좀만 더 잘래...
I'm gonna sleep more...
작작 좀 해!
Behave yourselves!
왜 매일 이렇게 되는 거야? 이제 질렸어.
Why does this happen every single day? I'm tired of it.
어, 트레이닝 배틀 신청이다!
Hey, it's a request for a training battle!
하루카, 빨리빨리!
Haruka, hurry up!
-뭐야모그?
-알고 있어.
-What's this-mogu?
-I know that.
무리야.
It's impossible.
어? 왜 거절한 거야! 오랜만의 트레이닝 배틀이 아깝게!
Hey, why did you refuse? That was a training battle of a while!
안 돼! 상대의 지정한 날에는 예정이 있어!
No! We already have plan in the day they requested.
자, 봐봐!
Look!
꽤 나중까지 정해져 있네.
We do have a lot of schedules!
여기 트레이닝 배틀 넣으면 되잖아! 여기도 들어가겠네!
We can have a training battle this day! Hey, this day too!
기계 조정은 어쩌게? 상대 분석은? 작전도 세워야 해.
What about machine configuration? Opponent analysis? We also need plans.
난 계속 싸우고 싶어! 더 싸우고 더 강해지고 싶어!
I want to keep fighting! I want to fight more and become stronger!
그러니까, 무리하면 다들 너덜너덜해진다니까.
I'm telling you that'll end up making everybody worn out!
이런 구멍 슝슝 뚫린 스케줄이면 다들 실력이 떨어질 거야!
With a schedule full of holes like this, everyone's abilities will go down!
맞아!
He's right!
실력이 떨어져모그!
We become worse-mogu!
-맞아맞아!
-구멍이 너무 많아!
-Right, right!
-Too many free times!
그럴 소리 할 거라면 알아서 멋대로 해.
If you're going to say that, then just do everything on your own.
그래, 하라면 한다! 매니저 일 따위 나도 할 수 있어!
Yeah, I will! I can do whatever manager does!
다들 해 봐, 간단해!
Everyone, try doing this! It's easy!
응응, 모레구나모그! 좋아모그! 받자모그!
Yeah, yeah, it's the day after tomorrow-mogu! Great-mogu! Let's accept this-mogu!
-이것도 받는 게 좋겠어!
-나도 해 볼래!
-We should take this too-mogu!
-Let me try!
-나도!
-Me too!
-아, 그거 아니야!
-뭐, 싸우잔 거야모그?!
-Hey, that's not it!
-What, wanna fight-mogu?!
진짜, 나 매니저 관둘래!
Really! I'm quitting this job!
흥! 어디 맘대로 해!
Hmph! Do as you wish!
어? 이제 몰라!
What?! I don't care anymore!
화났잖아, 아키라.
She's angry, Akira.
괜찮아, 저런 벽창호. 다들 트레이닝이 하고 싶어!
We don't need a blockhead like her! Everyone wants to do training!
-기분은 알겠다.
-나도 마찬가지지만, 다만...
-I do understand you.
-Me too, but...
걱정 마! 하루카 따위 없어도 전혀 문제 없어!
Don't worry! It's all fine even without Haruka!
뛰쳐나오긴 했는데, 이제 어쩐담...
Now that I've quit, what should I do from now on...
아이스크림! 아이스크림 사세요!
Ice creams! Take some ice creams!
아, 바닐라 하나!
One vanilla!
음, 최신형이라니 이런 거구나. 몰랐네. 바빴으니...
So these are how latest ones look like. I didn't know. I was so busy...
좋아!
Alright!
이제부터 어쩔까나.
What should I do from now on?
이스턴 로봇 컴패니.
Eastern Robot Company.
산업용 로봇 세계 점유율 제일. 최고의 기술력으로 여러분의 미래를 응원합니다.
Our market share in industrial robots is the highest in the world. We encourage your future with our technology!
우리 이스턴 로봇 컴패니는 당신을 부르고 있습니다.
Eastern Robot Company wants to work with you.
이스턴 로봇 컴패니에서는 지금 배틀 로봇 매니저를 대모집하고 있습니다.
Eastern Robot Company is now hiring battle robot managers.
이거야!
That's it!
당신에게 있어 배틀 로봇 매치는 뭡니까?
What does battle robot match mean to you?
제 정열을 모두 걸 수 있는 것입니다.
I can spend all my passion for those.
매니저라는 것은?
What is manager?
제 직업. 사는 보람입니다.
My job, and the worth of living.
그럼 마지막으로, 오코노미야끼하고 타코야끼, 지금 먹고 싶은 건 뭡니까?
FInally, what do you want to eat: Okonomiyaki or Takoyaki?
타코야끼!
Takoyaki!
판단 처리에 걸린 시간 0.77초. 판단 능력  7.
Judgement took 0.77 seconds. Judgement ability 7.
동공 개폐률 0.77%. 처리 능력 0.12. 위기 관리 능력 8.
Pupil shut 0.77%. Processing ability 0.12. Risk management ability 8.
코드 넘버 05, 호시 하루카.
Code number 05, Hoshi Haruka.
네, 네.
Y- yessir!
채용.
Hired.
어?
What?
채용입니다.
You're hired.
조, 좋아!
Y- yay!
노, 놀랐다... 여긴 어디야?
T- that surprised me... where am I?
당신의 방입니다.
It's your room.
누구?
Who are you?
저는 당신의 전속 비서 프로그램인 미스 포어입니다.
I am your exclusive secretary program, Miss Poire.
전속 비서 프로그램? 그렇구나, 매니저를 지원하는 프로그램이구나.
Exclusive secretary program? I see. It's a program that supports managers.
일어나 주십시오. 유니폼으로 갈아입혀 드리겠습니다.
Please stand up. I will change your clothes to uniform.
매니저의 유니폼과 ID 카드입니다.
It's a uniform for managers and that's an ID card.
지금부터 관리실에 갑니다. 자리에 앉아 주십시오.
You'll be located to the managing room. Please take a seat.
저들은 당신의 전속 서브 매니저 팀입니다. 저들의 임무는 담당하는 배틀 로봇 개발 팀에게서의 요청을 모아서
They are your exclusive team of sub-managers.
Their responsibility is to compile requests from the battle robot development teams in their charge,
당신에게 보고하고 지시를 전달하는 것입니다.
report it to you, and deliver instructions.
담당 개발 팀?
Development teams in their charge?
팀은 10개로 나뉘어 독립되어 개발하고 있습니다.
There are 10 teams, developing independently of each others.
복잡하네.
It sounds complicated.
그럼 지금부터 당신이 매니지할 로단 알파에 대해 설명드리겠습니다.
Then from now on, I'll explain about Rodan Alpha that you'll manage.
로단 알파라니, 유명한 팀 존의 배틀 로봇이잖아!
Rodan Alpha must be the battle robot of that famous Team John!
그렇습니다. 우리 이스턴 로봇 컴패니가 세계에 자랑하는 최신형 배틀 로봇입니다.
That's right. It's the latest battle robot that we Eastern Robot Company have pride in.
로단 알파는 시프터 타이프로, 어떤 배틀에도 대용 가능한 만능형.
Rodan Alpha is Shifter Type. It can face any battle, and is all-purpose.
적의 공격력이나 방어력을 순식간에 분식해 약점을 공격하는 능력은 우리 개발 팀이...
The ability of analyzing the enemy's weak point in a blink of eye and attacking that is developed by our development...
역시 일류 팀이야. 백업이 꽉 되어 있어. 오늘부터 나, 일류 매니저야!
This really is a top-class team. The backups are perfect. I'm a top-class manager, starting from today!
매니저 하루카.
Manager Haruka.
네, 네!
Y- yessir!
사인해 주세요.
Please sign.
사인?
Sign?
ID 카드를 넣어 주세요.
Swipe your ID card.
이걸로 오늘의 제 일은 종료입니다. 그럼 안녕히 주무십시오.
Then my work for today is done. See you tomorrow morning.
어, 저기... 여보세요?
Er, um... hello?
다들 잘 있을까...
I wonder if they're fine...
좋은 아침입니다. 10시부터 서브매니저로부터의 보고가 있습니다.
Good morning. You have reports from sub-managers from 10 o'clock.
네, 네...
Y- yessir...
그럼 ID 카드를 넣어 주세요.
Then, please swipe your ID card.
네!
Yeah!
보고 내용, 각 개발 팀에게서의 새 파트 발주.
Report: Order for parts from respective development teams.
팀 A: 원형 나사 하나. 이상.
Team A: Round screw 1ea. Over.
팀 B: B형 너트 하나. 이상.
Team B: B-type nut 1ea. Over.
팀 C: 대충격용 스프링 둘. 이상.
Team C: Anti-shock spring 2ea. Over.
알겠어.
Understood.
용인. 그럼 사인은.
Accepted. Then please sign.
완료입니다.
Your job is done.
됐다! 첫 일! 그럼 다음은!
I did my first work! What's next?
휴게입니다.
Break time.
휴게? 막 시작했잖아.
Break? I just started working!
보고 내용 확인에 88 칼로리, 보고 내용에 대한 찬성 판단에 98 칼로리.
88 calories spent to identify the contents of reports. 99 calories spent to make a approval decision.
그리고 사인 동작에 16 칼로리. 전 칼로리, 일 에너지에서 감산한 결과, 1시간의 휴게가 필요합니다.
And 16 calories spent to sign. Calculating from subtraction from work energy, you need one hour of break.
잠깐. 그거라면 휴게 동안 커맨더하고 만나서 이야기하고 싶어.
Wait. If I have time for that, I want to meet the commander and talk.
왜입니까?
For what?
작전을 세운다거나, 스케줄 이야기라던가, 여러가지 있잖아.
Make a plan, talk about schedules, and more.
각하. 만날 수 없습니다.
Rejected. You cannot meet them.
음, 무슨 소리야? 난 팀 존의 매니저잖아?
Hey, what are you talking about? I am Team John's manager.
매니저 하루카는 커맨더하고 만날 권한이 회사 규정 제 28조에 의해 주어져 있지 않습니다.
Manager Haruka does not have permission to meet the commander, per the 28th article of company policy.
회사 규정?!
Company policy?!
배틀 로봇 콘테스트 우승작
"싸우는 에디슨 고마 팬텀"
효고 현
모리타 쿠미 씨 (8살)
Battle Robot Contest Winner
"Fighting Edison Goma Phantom"
Morita Kumi (8 years old) in Hyogo
배틀 로봇 콘테스트 우승작
"헤비켄"
후쿠오카 현
스가하라 유지로 (7살)
Battle Robot Contest Winner
"Hebiken" (Snake Sword)
Sugahara Yuujiro (7 years old) in Fukuoka
다들 온다!
They're coming!
좋아!
Yeah!
근질근질하는걸!
I'm itching for action!
트레이닝 배틀로 이거라면...
This, as a training battle...
상대하기에 부족하지 않다.
They are perfect as our opponents.
개발 팀에게서 새로운 파트 추가 발주입니다.
Additional order for new parts from development team.
팀 D: 스크류식 D형 나사 하나, 이상.
Team D: D-type screw, 1ea. Over.
사인을.
Please sign.
잠깐만! 내 일, 파트 주문 받는 거 밖에 없어?
Hey! Is my only job processing part orders?
게다가 내 콘솔에서는 아무 데이터도 안 보이잖아!
Moreover, I can't see any data from my console!
호스트 컴퓨터의 위기 관리 프로그램에 의해 기밀 유출 방지가 되어 있습니다.
By the risk management program of the host computer, we have a secret protection scheme.
지금 바로 데이터를 보여줘! 매니저가 아무것도 모르면 팀에게 도움이 되는 게 하나도 없잖아?
Show me the data right now! If the manager doesn't know a thing, then it will only affect negatively to the team!
각하.
Rejected.
어? 왜?
Huh? Why?
규칙 위반입니다.
It's a violation of policy.
그럼 로단 알파한테 만나게 해줘. 내가 관리하는 배틀 로봇이니까.
Then let me meet Rodan Alpha. He's a battle robot I'm managing.
만나고 닿고 말을 거는 것도 중요한 일이잖아?
Meeting, touching, and talking are important things too, you know.
그런 요구를 한 매니저는 당신이 처음입니다.
You are the first manager to make those requests.
알겠습니다. 지금부터 중역에게 보고해 판단을 요구하겠습니다.
Understood. I will report this to the board of directors and ask for permissions.
그거 과장이지?
Are you exaggerating?
회사 규칙 제 8조에 의한 정당한 절차입니다.
It's a legitimate procedures, per the 8th article of the company policy.
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
공격!
Attack!
됐다!
We did it!
다음은 나다!
Next is me!
가자, 다들!
Let's go, everybody!
썬더 클로!
Thunder Claw!
테일 블레이드!
Tail Blade!
파이어 애로!
Fire Arrow!
클래시 뱅!
Clash Bang!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
여기가 우리 회사가 자랑하는 로단 알파 개발실 No. 4입니다.
This is the 4th Rodan Alpha Development Room of our company.
가까이 안 가면 의미가 없잖아.
If I can't go myself, then it's meaningless.
중역회에서 인정된 건 여기까지입니다. 그럼 원하는 만큼 즐겨 주십시오.
This is all allowed from the board of directors. Please enjoy.
어? 로단 알파는?
Huh? What about Rodan Alpha?
저게 그것입니다.
That is it.
저거 발이잖아?
That's just a leg!
당신은 로단 알파의 오른발을 관리하고 있습니다.
You are managing Rodan Alpha's right leg.
뭐? 오른발뿐이라고?!
What? Only right leg?!
밥이다, 밥!
Dinnertime!
어! 어, 없어! 내 먹을 게 아무것도 없어!
I- it's empty! I have nothing to eat!
뭐? 에너지 팩 조정이 안 되어 있으니까 먹으면 안 된다고?!
What?! You're saying that we can't eat those energy packs because they're not configured yet?!
-그런 거
-알 게 뭐야!
-Nobody cares
-about that!
-다 먹지 마!
-내 것도!
-나도!
-Don't eat them all!
-Let me eat mine!
-Me too!
그, 그래. 에너지 팩 조정이나 식품 주문은 하루카가 했었어...
R- right... Haruka configured the energy packs and ordered my foods...
아이고...
My life...
내가 맡은 건 로단 알파의 일부분. 그런 일이야...
What I'm managing is Rodan Alpha's single part. That's so...
그래도... 그래! 뭔가 가능한 게 있을 거야!
But... right! There should be something that I can do!
내 방식으로.
In my way, that is.
좋아!
Right!
호스트 컴퓨터에 침입해서 다른 데이터를 볼 수 있게 프로그램을 조금 바꿀래.
I'll invade into the host computer and modify the program so that I can see other data too.
OK. 이걸로 팀의 상황을 쉽게 알 수 있겠어.
Great. This will let me know the information about the team easily.
이번엔...
And now...
처음 보네. 나는 네 새로운 매니저 호시 하루카야.
Nice to meet you. I am your new manager, Hoshi Haruka.
뭐야, 이건? 조금 프로그램을 바꾸는 것만으로 더 힘이 나올 텐데.
What's this? A slight modification in the program will allow lot more power.
꼼짝 마라!
Do not move!
다, 다이간다, 드래곤 캐논...
D- Daigunder, use Dragon Cannon...
드래곤 캐논.
Dragon Cannon.
공격!
Attack!
어, 어딜 쏘냐!
W- where are you aiming at?!
으랏차차.
Heave-ho.
어이, 거기. 어이, 너, 거기 앉아.
Hey, you. You over there. Sit.
들어 봐라. 내가 어릴 적에는 말이다...
Listen. When I was young...
브라이온! 뭐 하고 있어?!
Bullion! What are you doing?!
파이어!
Fire!
누가 나 멈춰 줘!
Someone stop me-mogu!
드리모그!
Drimog!
나 따위...
I...
쓸모 없어.
am not needed.
싸워, 이글 애로!
Fight, Eagle Arrow!
정신 차려, 트라이혼!
Calm down, Trihorn!
왜 이렇게 슬픈 거야! 얘도 쟤도 지옥에나 가 버려!
Why am I so sad?! You and you! Go to hell!
데스펙터!
Despector!
모두 자신의 시스템에 맞지 않는 걸 먹어서 이상해지고 말았다.
Everyone became strange because we ate things that are not for our systems.
에이, 작작 좀 해 줘!
Please, stop it!
코드 넘버 05. 당신은 매니저로서의 일을 착각하고 있는 것 같다.
Code number 05. It seems that you're mistaken about a manager's job.
저는 제 사고방식에 문제는 없다고 생각합니다.
I think I am not wrong.
문제가 없어?
Not wrong?
데이터를 숨기기만 해선 안 됩니다. 특히, 매니저에게 데이터는 중요한 판단 재료입니다.
You shouldn't be only hiding the data. To managers, data are critical in making decisions.
그래야 배틀 로봇에도 발전이 있습니다. 인간과 같이 만나야 합니다.
That's the only way for battle robots to be improved. They have to meet, just like humans do.
그건 효율성을 무시한 방식이다.
That is an inefficient way.
매니저라면 언제 어디서라도 팀에 대해서 뭐든지 알아야 합니다.
A manager must know everything about the team no matter where or when.
배틀 로봇과 만나며, 무엇을 원하는지 알아야 합니다.
We have to meet battle robots by ourselves and find out what do they want.
-참으로 비논리적이다.
-이게 팀 아키라의 방식입니다.
-That is illogical.
-This is the way of Team Akira.
전근대적인 팀이다. 같은 취급하면 곤란하다.
It is a premodern team. You have to move on.
난 어쨌든...
For me...
팀 아키라를 업신여기면 용서 못 해!
I can't forgive anyone who look down of Team Akira!
저 관둡니다.
I quit.
안녕히.
Bye.
결원 1명. 새로운 매니저를 시급히 모집하시오.
One vacancy. Hire a new manager as soon as possible.
-하루카가 있었다면
-이렇게는 안 됐어모그.
-If Haruka was here,
-this would have never happened.
매니저를... 동료를 하나 잃은 게 이렇게나 큰 일이 될 줄이야.
I never thought losing a manager... a friend would result in something this bad.
우리는 앞으로 어떻게 되나.
What will happen to us from now on?
이게 죄다!
All of this...!
뭐야! 내 탓이란 거야?
What?! You're blaming me?!
그렇게는 말 안 했어. 말은 안 했는데...
We didn't say that. We didn't, but...
역시 말하는 거잖아! 정말..
You are saying so! Really...
있잖아, 다같이 사과하자.
Hey, let's apologize all together.
그래! 다같이 하루카한테 사과하자.
Yeah! Let's apologize to Haruka all together.
음...
Hmm...
아키라.
Akira.
아키라!
Akira!
네, 네, 사과하면 되잖아? 사과하면.
Yeah, yeah, I'll apologize. I'll say sorry.
뭐야, 그 태도는.
What's wrong with that attitude?
-아키라가 이렇게 만들었잖아!
-너 때문에 이렇게 됐어모그!
-잘못한 줄 알아야지!
-잘한 것 없는 놈이 거만하다!
-You caused all of this, Akira!
-This is all because of you-mogu!
-You should be ashamed of yourself!
-How arrogant of you!
알았어. 사과할게. 다 함께. 나, 사과할게.
All right. I'll apologize. All together. I'll say sorry.
좋아! 그렇게 나와야지!
Great! You should have said that eariler!
다만 사과한다 해도 하루카가 어디에 있는지...
But even if we're to apologize, we don't know where Haruka is.
그렇다. 때는 이미 늦었다.
Right. We are too late.
어? 좋은 생각이 있다고?
What? You have an idea?
다시 뛰쳐나왔네. 이제 어쩐담...
Now that I've quit again, what should I do from now on...
아이스크림! 아이스크림 사세요!
Ice creams! Get some ice creams!
어, 저... 오늘은 하늘이 맑고...
Um, err... today's sky is clear...
뭔 소리야, 아키라!
What are you saying, Akira?!
하루카, 보고 있어? 만약 보고 있으면 들어 줘!
Haruka, are you watching? If you are, then please listen to us!
우리가 잘못했어!
We were bad!
하루카가 없어지니 다들 깨달았어! 매니저의 일이 얼마나 어려운 일인지!
We all have realized during you were gone, Haruka! We realized how difficult it is to be a manager!
모두를 위해서 얼마나 힘써 주는지! 우리는 역시 하루카가 필요해!
We realized that you were working so hard for everyone! We need you, Haruka!
그러니까!
Please!
-하루카!
-하루카! 우리가 잘못했어!
-Haruka!
-Haruka! We were bad!
바보.
Idiots.
바보...
Idiots...
하루카! 어서 돌아와!
Haruka! Please come back soon!
기다리고 있을게!
We're waiting for you!
하루카! 어서 돌아와!
Haruka! Come back soon!
아키라! 일어나! 아키라도 참.
Akira, wake up! Akira!
계속 자고 있지만 말고!
Don't keep sleeping like that!
좀만 더...
A little bit more...
일어나라니까!
Wake up!
끝없는 꿈을 꾸고 있어
Dreaming an endless dream
Я сон бесконечный вижу опять перед собой
몇번이고 쓰러져도
I fall down over and over again
Как упал, и лечу вниз вновь и вновь.
저 구름 위에는 분명히
Up over those clouds
Там, где-то в высотах, за чертой облаков
푸른 하늘이 펼쳐져 있을 거야
a blue sky awaits
голубое небо ждёт меня!
강해지기 위해서라면 누구도 혼자서는
To be strong, nobody can ever become
Сильным быть, чтоб никто превзойти не смог
강해지고 뜨거워질 수 없어
strong and hot, by oneself
Стать сильней, горячей, сам я хочу!
불꽃의 Fight Fight Fighting soul
Flaming fightin' fightin' fighting soul
Так гори, душа, душа бойца!
용기를 마주치는 그 때
When you face your courage
Смелость повстречай, и пусть ведёт она тебя в жизни.
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
느껴져 바로 너라는 게
I can feel it, yes, it's you
Я это чувствую, да, это ты!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
둘은 서로의 영웅
The two are heroes of each other
Два героя - части одного, нерушимы связи,
질 수 없는 같은 내일을
They run towards to the same tomorrow
Вместе в новый день по одной тропе спешат
바라보고 달려
that they cannot lose
И не собьются с неё!
이번 우리 상대인 칸은 엄청 지독한 놈이야!
Our opponent Karn is really strict!
그러니까, 배틀이 막 끝났는데 쉬지도 않고 바로 훈련!
Like, as soon as their battle was over, they started to train right away, without taking a rest!
그래도, 그 지독함 뒤에는 훌륭한 결심이 있었어!
But behind that strictness, there was a splendid determination!
그런 칸의 팀을 드라고버스트가 노렸어!
And then Dragoburst is aiming for them!
네가 얘들을 방해하게 두지 않을 거야! 가자, 다이간다! 드래곤 캐논!
I won't let you interfere with them! Let's do this, Daigunder! Dragon Cannon!
폭투선언 다이간다의 다음 이야기!
근성선언! 도깨비 커맨더의 정!!
Next time on Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
Guts Declaration! The Bond of Fierce Commander!!